Finding Aid for United States Army Signal Corps photograph collection 1918-1919
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs
  - Oversize prints, 41 prints (Folder 11)
    - Print No. 158849 April 8, 1919 (Item 29)
      (American soldiers who were engaged in fighting near the village of Bolshie Ozerka, a point on the Allied line of communication, between Obozerskaya and Onega, had to live under trying conditions. Here are shown tents which were used by men of the 3rd Platoon, Co. "C" 310th Engrs. The tents were pitched in the snow among the forest trees near Verst-18 85th Div. Bolshie Ozerka, Russia.)
    - Print No. 158851 April 5, 1919 (Item 30)
    - Print No. 158852 April 5, 1919 (Item 31)
      (Officers of Co. "M", 339th Inf. 85th Div. Immediately after the return of the company from Bolshie Ozerka front where they repulsed repeated Bolshevik attacks. >From L. to R: Lt. Clarence J. Primm, 2nd Lt. Milton J. Carpenter, 2nd Lt. Weiszorek, Lt. Wesley K. Wright, Lt. James R. Donovan, Lt. George M. Stoner, and Capt. Joel Moore. Obozerskaya, Russia.)
    - Print No. 158853 April 5, 1919 (Item 32)
      (An officer and two men of Co. "M", 339th Inf. 85th Div, on their return from a weeks fighting near Bolshie Ozerka, L to R: Lt. James R. Donovan, Cpl. Benjamin Jondre, Pvt. Jens Jenson, Obozerskaya, Russia.)
    - Print No. 158859 April 8, 1919 (Item 33)
      (A closed view of blockhouse No. 2 taken from a point on the Bolshie Ozerka Road, near Verst 18. 339th Inf. 85th Div. Bolshie Ozerka Front. Russia.)
    - Print No. 158862 April 8, 1919 (Item 34)
      (Russian 75s and Russian artillerymen stationed at Verst 16. Splendid work was done by this artillery in shelling the village of Bolshie Ozerka and in defeating an attempted flank attack by a strong Bolshevik patrol. 339th Inf. 85th Div. Bolshie Ozerka Front, Russia.)
    - Print No. 158863 April 8, 1919 (Item 35)
    - Print No. 158870 April 8, 1919 (Item 36)
    - Print No. 158871 April 8, 1919 (Item 37)
    - Print No. 150874 April 8, 1919 (Item 38)
    - Print No. 158880 April 9, 1919 (Item 39)
    - Print No. 158884 April 9, 1919 (Item 40)
      (View of a part of the clearing at Verst 444 showing path through the woodpiles cut by enemy shells. Artillery fire directed against this position has destroyed all buildings and scattered fire wood in every direction. 339th Inf. 85th Div. Vologda Railway Front, Russia.)
    - Print No. 161702 March 14, 1919 (Item 41)
  - Unnumbered and outsize photos, 9 items (Folder 12)
    The unnumbered photographs (9 1/2" x 12") are Signal Corps images but are not described in the list in Folder 1. They were distributed by the Committee of Public Information of the United States of America, Bern [Switzerland]. The photos include captions in French or German. Most are annotated with a handwritten English translation. There is also a single, uncredited photo (11" x 14") of a reindeer taxi near Archangel.
    - Railroad Station temporarily turned into hospital Oberskaya, Russia, September 1918 (Item 1)
    - Street Car in Archangel, Russia. American soldiers broke the street car strike, September 1918 (Item 2)
    - One company of Americans going forward along railroad tracks to defend a bridge September 30, 1918 (Item 3)
    - Ceremony of taking possession of Archangel Hospital (Item 4)
    - American and Russian soldiers on fortified coal car, 125 miles from Archangel (Item 5)
    - Unloading the first American ambulances destined for the Expeditionary Force. (Item 6)
    - President Wilson and party arriving at Brest, France (Item 7)
    - Reindeer Taxi on frozen Dwina River near Archangel (Item 8)
    - Print No. 158852 April 5, 1919 (Item 9)